Brandon Shurick

Pragmatic Business Intelligence Engineer and Data Scientist; recent graduate of the Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS) program from UC Berkeley; Extensive experience with SQL and Python for data processing and analysis. 11036 E Riverside Dr.
Bothell, WA 98011
(253)-222-2982
brandon.shurick@gmail.com
http://brandonshurick.com

EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Seattle — Business Intelligence Engineer

OCTOBER 2016 - PRESENT

Data warehouse management, data modeling, production machine learning model creation and deployment using Python, ad hoc data analysis using Redshift/SQL and Python.

TravelBird, Amsterdam — Sr. BI Engineer / Data Scientist

JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2016

Responsible for AB testing analysis and development of customer-facing product recommendation engine using Apache Spark, development and maintenance of global business intelligence dashboards using Tableau, Python, Vertica/SQL.

Westwing Group GmbH, Munich — *Sr. BI / DWH Developer*

JULY 2014 - MAY 2015

Led global business intelligence infrastructure improvements, including migration of data warehouse from MySQL to Vertica, and contributed to inferential analysis of customer and operational data using R.

T-Mobile USA, Bellevue — Sr. Product Engineer, Analyst

JANUARY 2009 - JUNE 2014

Created data product prototypes, analyzed mobile device data of large scale from Hadoop using Hive, developed interactive data visualizations and dashboards using Tableau and JavaScript / HTML.

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley, Berkeley — Master of Information and Data Science

JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2016

Data science coursework and projects spanning a diverse range of topics, including data visualization, descriptive and inferential statistics, machine learning at scale, experiments, and big data processing.

University of Washington, Seattle — Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration (Finance, Information Systems)

SEPTEMBER 2004 - JUNE 2008

Business administration studies with additional coursework in Finance and Information Systems.

SKILLS

Python Sklearn & Scipy stack

SQL and data modeling

Data visualization and analysis

Big Data architectures

Web development

AWARDS

Hal R. Varian MIDS

Capstone Award Recognition
for top project out of UC
Berkeley MIDS Capstone
submissions, Summer 2016

Annual Dean's List University of Washington 2007–2008

PROJECTS

MIDS Capstone Project (http://goaltick.info)

Data Storage & Retrieval Streaming Twitter Storage (http://goo.gl/U3yZvq)

Field Experiment: Video or Text Math Education (https://bit.ly/2kM3wPj)